[
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 18,
        "y_pos1": 1,
        "move": 128,
        "id": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Mariah",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A young mage",
            "job": "I seek adventure!",
            "heal": "Quite good.",
            "keyword1": "ADVE",
            "keyword2": "QUES",
            "answer1": "Yes, I hope to go on a great quest!",
            "answer2": "The quest of the avatar is noble indeed!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou on a quest?",
            "yesanswer": "I wish I could join thee!",
            "noanswer": "Wish thou were!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 1,
        "tile1": 33,
        "x_pos1": 8,
        "y_pos1": 5,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Tracie",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "Starving journalist",
            "job": "I am a writer.",
            "heal": "I feel fine... if I could just quit smoking!",
            "keyword1": "WRIT",
            "keyword2": "SMOK",
            "answer1": "It's low paid, but glamorous!",
            "answer2": "Cough...cough...",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you smoke?",
            "yesanswer": "I can tell by the smell!",
            "noanswer": "Don't start!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 34,
        "x_pos1": 28,
        "y_pos1": 3,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 2,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Cromwell",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A regal paladin.",
            "job": "I speak of the virtues of honesty!",
            "heal": "Well indeed.",
            "keyword1": "HONE",
            "keyword2": "MANT",
            "answer1": "A few honest men are better than numbers!",
            "answer2": "The mantra of the shrine of honesty is 'AHM'.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou strive to be honest?",
            "yesanswer": "Then you will need the mantra.",
            "noanswer": "Shame!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 43,
        "x_pos1": 18,
        "y_pos1": 6,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 3,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Rebelias",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A mystic wizard.",
            "job": "I live an honest life.",
            "heal": "I've been better",
            "keyword1": "HONE",
            "keyword2": "EVIL",
            "answer1": "Speak the truth and shame the evil forces!",
            "answer2": "Evil still exists in our hearts and souls!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou seek to conquer thine own evil?",
            "yesanswer": "The quest of a lifetime!",
            "noanswer": "Wretch!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 32,
        "x_pos1": 20,
        "y_pos1": 6,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 4,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Christen",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A playful child.",
            "job": "I am your friend.",
            "heal": "Feeling good.",
            "keyword1": "FRIE",
            "keyword2": "HONE",
            "answer1": "Honest friends are few!",
            "answer2": "My friend William knows where the rune of honesty is.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou my friend?",
            "yesanswer": "That makes me happy.",
            "noanswer": "I am sad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 5,
        "tile1": 91,
        "x_pos1": 24,
        "y_pos1": 6,
        "move": 1,
        "id": 5,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Patric the Humble Shepherd",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A meek shepherd.",
            "job": "I am shepherd.",
            "heal": "Pretty good.",
            "keyword1": "HUMB",
            "keyword2": "HUMI",
            "answer1": "Humility is not derived from the direct combination of truth, love or courage.",
            "answer2": "Humility is to act and be humble.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou totally humble?",
            "yesanswer": "Doubtful!",
            "noanswer": "Strive to be."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 6,
        "tile1": 46,
        "x_pos1": 28,
        "y_pos1": 20,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 6,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Shazom",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A dying young wizard.",
            "job": "I am apprentice to the great wizard Nigel!",
            "heal": "I will soon die.",
            "keyword1": "NIGE",
            "keyword2": "DIE ",
            "answer1": "I will soon need to use the spell he calls 'recall'.",
            "answer2": "Pass on.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou met Nigel?",
            "yesanswer": "Seek him out for he will teach thee.",
            "noanswer": "He lives at the Lycaeum."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 56,
        "x_pos1": 28,
        "y_pos1": 22,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 7,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Shakespeare",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A wise wizard.",
            "job": "I create tales of honesty.",
            "heal": "Getting on.",
            "keyword1": "HONE",
            "keyword2": "CORR",
            "answer1": "Remember, there is no terror in threats for I am strong in honesty!",
            "answer2": "Corruption wins not more than honesty!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou strive to be honest?",
            "yesanswer": "Beware corruption!",
            "noanswer": "Fool!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 8,
        "tile1": 33,
        "x_pos1": 5,
        "y_pos1": 28,
        "move": 1,
        "id": 8,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Browning",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall mage.",
            "job": "I strive to live an honest life!",
            "heal": "Been better.",
            "keyword1": "HONE",
            "keyword2": "TRUT",
            "answer1": "An honest soul need remember no lies!",
            "answer2": "Truth is the root of honesty!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou never lied?",
            "yesanswer": "That seems unlikely!",
            "noanswer": "Truth never hurts the teller!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 32,
        "x_pos1": 3,
        "y_pos1": 27,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 9,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Cosima",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "An elderly woman",
            "job": "I am an alchemist.",
            "heal": "Tired, so tired.",
            "keyword1": "ALCH",
            "keyword2": "REAG",
            "answer1": "I know how best to mix reagents!",
            "answer2": "A sleep spell actually requires but one part spider silk!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou know how to best mix spells?",
            "yesanswer": "Good!",
            "noanswer": "The secret's in the reagents!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 33,
        "x_pos1": 21,
        "y_pos1": 10,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 10,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Daranor",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A hunched, insane looking man!",
            "job": "I move the sun!",
            "heal": "Health?",
            "keyword1": "SUN ",
            "keyword2": "MOON",
            "answer1": "The moons are my enemies!",
            "answer2": "When I die the world will end!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you believe my story!?!?...",
            "yesanswer": "Then we must fell the moons!",
            "noanswer": "Idiot, you must think I am insane!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 11,
        "tile1": 88,
        "x_pos1": 2,
        "y_pos1": 22,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 11,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Inoo",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "An old gypsy.",
            "job": "I am a fortune teller, I read palms.",
            "heal": "I predict I will be fine today!",
            "keyword1": "PALM",
            "keyword2": "FORT",
            "answer1": "Palms tell fortunes!",
            "answer2": "Give thy palm.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou wish thy destiny?",
            "yesanswer": "A great quest will lead thee into the abyss where the codex awaits!",
            "noanswer": "Wise choice."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 12,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 21,
        "y_pos1": 28,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 12,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Calabrini",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall mage.",
            "job": "I bear greetings from the fair city of Moonglow.",
            "heal": "Fine.",
            "keyword1": "INN ",
            "keyword2": "HEAL",
            "answer1": "We have an excellent inn.",
            "answer2": "Our healer is one of the best!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou seek an inn or healing?",
            "yesanswer": "Which?",
            "noanswer": "Perhaps, the shrine which lies on an isle to the north!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 13,
        "tile1": 32,
        "x_pos1": 6,
        "y_pos1": 14,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 13,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Dekker",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A bouncy jester",
            "job": "I earn an honest living, jesting!",
            "heal": "Very good.",
            "keyword1": "HONE",
            "keyword2": "JEST",
            "answer1": "Honest labor bears a lovely face!",
            "answer2": "I love a good jest.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou?",
            "yesanswer": "We ought to exchange jokes sometime!",
            "noanswer": "Thou art probably a sourpuss!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 87,
        "x_pos1": 4,
        "y_pos1": 7,
        "move": 1,
        "id": 14,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "William",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A child eating a sandwich.",
            "job": "Oh, not much.",
            "heal": "Pretty good.",
            "keyword1": "SAND",
            "keyword2": "RUNE",
            "answer1": "It's a peanut butter and grape jelly on lightly toasted bread!",
            "answer2": "Search for the rune of honesty by Mariah's gold!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wouldst thou like a bite?",
            "yesanswer": "Yummy, huh!",
            "noanswer": "It's awful yummy!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 15,
        "tile1": 91,
        "x_pos1": 28,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 15,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Tyrone",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A battered mage.",
            "job": "I used to search for the blue stone.",
            "heal": "Fading.",
            "keyword1": "STON",
            "keyword2": "USE ",
            "answer1": "The stone of honesty is found on an altar in the dungeon of Deceit.",
            "answer2": "It is used within the dungeon altar rooms and in the abyss.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wilt thou search?",
            "yesanswer": "Know its uses!",
            "noanswer": "Hmm."
        }
    }
]